♪ In the
not-too-distant future ♪
♪ next sunday a.d. ♪
♪˯ there was a guy
named joel ♪
♪˯ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked at
gizmonic institute ♪
♪˯ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪˯ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪˯ but his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space ♪
♪♪
♪˯ we'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪˯ and we'll
monitor his mind ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪˯ now keep in mind
joel can't control ♪
♪˯ where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪˯ to make
his robot friends ♪
♪♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
- ♪˯ cambot ♪
- pan left!
- ♪ Gypsy ♪
- hi, girl!
- ♪ Tom servo ♪
- what a cool guy!
- ♪˯ croooow ♪
- he's a wisecracker.
♪˯ if you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪˯ and other science facts ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪˯ then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪˯ I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for
mystery science theater 3000 ♪
♪♪
[Mechanical whirring]
Okay, what is it?
It's the nbc mystery movie.
Uh-huh.
[Electrical buzzing]
Oh, gah--ah,
thank you, sir.
May I have another?
Oh, sure.
All right.
Oh, hi, everybody.
Welcome to
the satellite of love.
I'm joel robinson,
these are my bots,
and we're doing a little
behavior modification
up here on the old
satellite of love.
You see, every experiment we do,
if you've been watching,
these two little robots
always say...
Nbc mystery movie...
When they see a flashlight
in the film,
and every time they say...
Nbc mystery movie...
They get a mild
but memorable shock.
[Electrical buzzing]
Whew! Oh, boy.
Hey, what was
that last one for?
Oh, the last one was for--
you know, you did it
the first time,
and then you did it again
the second time.
Oh, right. Go ahead.
Wait, wait, wait.
Did what? Did what?
Uh, said
nbc mystery movie.
Oh!
[Laughs]
Okay, all right, okay.
Come on, dr. Skinner.
[Electrical buzzing]
I taste copper.
Oh, we'll be right back.
Okay, let's get working
on the suit.
How come we don't get
our own extra show?
♪♪
Hi, everybody.
Well, it looks like
mutt and jeff
are in charge of the invention
exchange this week, and--
and joel, as everybody knows,
except maybe you,
that the olfactory
or sense of smell
is our greatest
memory enhancer.
Yes, as opposed
to accent seasoning,
which is
a flavor enhancer.
Mm, quite,
so now, we have created
the world's first scratch
and sniff report card.
Exactly, uh, so one scratch
and one smell,
and parents are transported
back to those painful days
of junior high.
The scratch and sniff report
card kind of helps take the edge
off getting a bad grade.
Too true, on account of
the smells of 'em kind of
makin' 'em remember
what school was like
then, there.
Well put.
Okay, let me see.
[Sniffing]
Say, it's true! It smells
like a habitrail. Pungent!
Exactly. You're in
biology class, silly!
Try the next one.
Oh, okay.
This is my favorite.
[Sniffing]
Ew!
It smells like burning
acetate and old dutch
cheese curls.
It's extracurricular
activities, joel, and you're
an av geek, mister!
[Laughter]
Join our groovy gang.
Let's watch the next one.
Oh, okay, well, this next
one seems simple enough.
What could really happen?
[Sniffing]
Uhh! It smells like that stuff
they put on throw up!
[Laughs]
Very observant, joel.
It turns out lisa smithback
is allergic to pink coconut
frosting--
hence, the vomit.
Oh, well, whatever.
You know, uh, this one
you're holding down here
smells really good.
Oh, well, I'm glad
you found it.
Uh, this is a special
report card my partner tom
and I developed
for expensive private
academies because, joel,
privilege has its own odor.
Polo.
What do you think, sirs?
Joel, grades aren't
important. Pfft!
IT'S THE S.A.T.s
THAT COUNT.
Well, now the good doctor
and I would like to
make a prediction
about the next big trend
in entertainment.
Move over, comedy clubs.
Move over,
trendy discussion salons.
Move over, karaoke bars.
Here comes ventriloquism--
big, broad, sassy,
and brassy.
And now, deep 13, in
association with george
slaughter productions,
would like to present the
ventriloquistic stylings
of dr. Clayton forrestor
and his loveable sidekick,
resusci-annie.
[Applause]
Hello.
This is resusci-annie.
We've secured over 2,000
of these previously-owned
cpr demonstration dolls
and retrofitted them with
ventriloquist animations
in anticipation of the
ventriloquist boom of the '90s.
And without further ado,
it's time to sit back
and laugh and learn
with resusci-annie.
[Laughs and clears throat]
Well, say hello to
the nice folks, resusci.
Hello, nice folks.
Resusci, I implore you to be
kind and courteous
to these well-meaning and clean,
uh, people here today.
I want to go find
some chicks!
[Laughs]
But resusci,
you is a chick.
I said,
resusci, you is a chick.
Uh, frank, uh,
something's wrong.
It-- this looks like
the big one.
I'll revive resusci and
tell joel about the movie.
You-- you dial 911
while drinking water!
Uh, your film today, joel,
is a, uh,
uh, a little film
which stars no one.
Uh, it features a giant,
lame lobster
and, uh, oh...
[Spraying]
[Mumbling through
mouthful of water]
Breathe, 2, 3, 4.
It's called teenagers
from outer space,
and it is a spunky load
of noodles.
Boy, is it ever out there.
That's an odd taste.
Send 'em the movie,
frank.
[Sniffing]
Health class?
Brrrrrrr!
[Mechanical whirring]
I'm sorry about the smell.
I can't get the stink out.
Oh, is he any relation
to christie love?
Get david love!
Look!
Oh.
According to erma bombeck,
all teenagers are
from outer space.
Oh, enough said.
[Laughter]
That spaceship
looks like a sun hat.
I think it's
a photographer's umbrella.
It's a giant metal falsie.
No, I think it's a devo hat.
Oh, no, it's a silo hot.
It's audrey hepburn's hat
from breakfast at tiffany's.
Guys, it can be all
those things and more.
You're right.
I like joel's plan.
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Let's work with joel
this time.
♪♪
[Clears throat]
And...
Oh, the great
c.R. Kaltenthaler.
[Laughter and mumbling]
Oh, I'm a writer,
producer, and director,
but I really want to grip.
Gr--hmm?
Run, toto, run!
♪˯ doo doo doo doo
doo doo doo ♪
Oh, it's won-ton-ton,
the dog that saved hollywood...
Almost.
Pac man.
Mee-nee-mee-nee...
♪♪
I am the egg man,
ooh, coo, cah-choo.
[Dog barking]
[Electronic pulsing]
Ooh, now michael jackson
will want him.
♪♪
Looks like the elephant man
in the 25th century.
♪♪
Ray liotta!
Ever since I was a kid,
I always wanted to be
a space man.
♪ I know I'd go from
rags to riches ♪
♪♪
They came all the way
to go bowling?
Huh?
Wow, really old teenagers
from outer space.
Mm-hmm.
Boy, I could sure go
for a hamburger sandwich
and some
french fried potatoes.
I'm a teenager, after all.
Welcome to
death valley days.
The driver is either
me or...
But they're all
wearing v-necks.
It must be student council
from outer space.
[Laughs]
♪♪
You know, a fella
could get used to this.
Yeah.
♪♪
Oh, cool, they got
marshall amps.
Custom heads.
♪♪
I travel light
just to make it back.
♪♪
When tv repairmen
walked the earth!
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Hey, it's harry connick jr.
Hmm?
You know you won't see
costuming like this
until marc singer does v.
Or thomas pynchon
does v.
♪♪
I will pet him and keep him
and call him george.
It's very sad, really.
Yeah.
Hmm, are you hungry?
Stay.
[Electronic beeping]
Oh, okay,
whose beeper is that?
[Beeping]
Now, I've got every shade
for every complexion.
♪♪
I see you have a machine
that goes "ping."
Huh?
What?
Oh.
It's a multichannel mixer!
It says so!
Report preliminary findings.
Thor reporting.
I've taken my pill, sir.
42 saturation degrees
and 96 volumes.
Of beer on the wall.
Intermediate fluctuation
in marphon content.
Derek reporting.
Hi, derek.
Tridex mixer components ratio
exceeding 7 to 1.4.
Moreal reporting.
Diagonal adjustment reading
resisting structural forms
by 2.8.0 vernams.
Saul reporting.
Dog gone.
[Laughs]
Uneven cartoid levels
intersect plains below .03.
♪ Shannon is gone,
they say she drifted
off to... ♪
Dry as a bone, huh?
Heh!
Hey, I think I found
the top of your thermos.
Surface readings register
above minimum requirements.
Moreal!
Go below and bring up
the young gargon specimen.
Buh-buh.
Now the decision depends
on its reactions.
Wait, captain.
I have found evidence of
intelligent beings
on this planet.
Of what concern
are foreign beings?
Of none to you, thor.
Cat fight.
[Hisses]
Just as you were so
unconcerned when you
destroyed this small creature.
Woof.
So bravely.
It was no more
than an insect.
But it had life,
and that life you had to take
to satisfy your endless
hunger for killing.
Silence, both of you!
He started it!
Proceed.
Bring the gargon.
That will not be necessary,
captain.
Mrs. Carmichael,
put that laser down.
Conditions here will be
reported as unsatisfactory,
as they were on the other
planets we have charted.
By what authority--
you will prepare
for takeoff!
The ship will leave
this planet immediately.
According to our code of
operations--
you may forget the code of
operations, captain!
I'm the code
of operations now!
Only civilized beings could
have made the inscription
on this metal piece.
We shall not have the thousands
of gargons brought here
to destroy them.
You have concern for foreign
beings over our mission
to locate grazing land
for our gargon herds?
Yep.
Thank you,
captain exposition.
Recall. It is necessary
as a reserve food supply
for our people.
Our people?
We live like parts
of a machine.
We don't know our
fathers or mothers.
We're raised in cubicles.
The sick and the old
are put to death.
It is the one and only way to
maintain the supreme race.
Have you forgotten that--
our people have forgotten.
Uh, maybe you should have
brought this up in group.
They have been made to forget
for centuries.
But I have
learned how it once was.
Families...
Brothers and sisters.
There was happiness.
There was love.
Oh, bite me,
there was not.
Of what do you speak?
From where have you
learned such things?
I have read.
I have read from this book.
Oh, a separate peace.
I discovered it
and kept it hidden.
He's got the book.
Somehow it survived the flames
of the annihilators
when our people were turned
into mechanized slaves
centuries ago.
When we return to our planet,
the high court may well
sentence you to torture...
Torture!
And death for this treason.
The high court may judge me
after we have accomplished
our mission.
But the court of earthen beauty
will back me all the way!
We will find an uninhibited
planet to which the herds
of gargons may be shipped,
without endangering
civilized beings.
Let me see that book.
I think what our bright
young friend is trying
to tell us is...
I am interested to see what
sways your mind so heavily.
♪♪
You may have it.
It's called iron john.
♪ Dah dah dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah ♪
Bring up the gargon.
I'll need an ipecac.
You are a fool, derek.
This book has poisoned
your mind, and you shall
suffer for it.
Captain, if the gargons are
shipped here, the inhabitants
may destroy them.
That possibility alone
makes it worthwhile to locate
an uninhabited planet.
He certainly is
a whisper-thin lad, isn't he?
That book has indeed
made you forget many things.
We are the supreme race.
We have the supreme weapons.
We have
the supreme pizzas!
Keep him under guard, thor.
I will study the reactions
of the young gargon.
I hate him, I hate him,
I hate him!
♪♪
Now, I like you, trevor,
but you're screwy,
you got it?
I'm the fellow wearing
the roscoe, see?
I like dames
but they don't like me.
Before the high court
has you executed,
you should be made to
watch what happens
when we return here
with the gargons.
By the elements alone,
they will grow to millions of
times their original size
in less time than it takes
for the sun to rise and fall.
You mean a day?
It thrives, captain.
♪˯ thrive, captain,
thrive ♪
Already, I can feel
it has grown heavier.
We should return to
our base and lead
the transport ships here.
Soon this planet
will be covered with
full-grown gargons.
And I will rule the world!
A safe distance
from our planet,
yet their meat will be
available to us
for the harvesting.
Repack the instruments.
I shall radio back
the news of our success.
Derek,
the sensitive space man.
♪♪
You'll pay for this!
Captain! Captain,
something has gone wrong.
Aw, criminy, what now?
What?
What has happened?
I do not know.
It suddenly fell limp
and now does not move.
Pull my finger!
Assemble the t-resses.
Hook in the gas grading
instruments.
Be quick!
Kwi kwag?
Hey, maybe you shouldn't have
put him in a snare drum.
Mm-mmm.
Oh, they're gonna
get him cable!
Oh!
Peter and annette
had one of those.
♪♪
The atmosphere here
tested above minimum...
Wage.
But the gargon species
cannot live
due to excessive nitrogenic
gas compounds emitted in our
preliminary diagnosis.
Try saying that
three times fast.
Then this planet will be
reported as unsuitable?
Oh, you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Repack the instruments
and prepare for takeoff.
This bites!
We will continue our search
in another solar system.
Yes, yes, yes!
And when we return
to our home base,
you will be presented to the
high court with the evidence
against you.
Torture!
Thor, saul...
Mort sahl?
Bind the prisoner
and prepare him for
the isolation chamber.
What's the question?
I will make contact
with base.
Okay.
♪♪
He is escaping!
Oh, gotta go.
Be back.
♪♪
No, thor!
Moses? Moses!
How did he get free?
He escaped from saul.
I could have stopped him.
Derek is to be
brought back alive.
He's the son of our leader.
Derek?
I reported his actions
and was connected
with the leader himself.
A real nice guy.
He told me this.
He said derek does not know.
As the son of our leader,
the high court will pardon him.
Oh, yeah,
he's a kennedy.
He will be pardoned.
Oh, yeah.
When the sky is light,
we will begin to search for him.
What? It is light.
Captain, look at this.
The gargon, it is not dead.
I'm not dead.
I'm getting better.
It has revived.
It flourishes.
The excessive nitrogenic gas
compounds shocked its system.
Now it thrives
on the very same compounds.
Then this planet
is suitable.
Completely.
I must resume
radiovision contact.
Pull my finger,
pull my finger.
Moreal, saul,
secure the gargon
by expandable leg bands.
Expandable leg bands?
Yes, sir!
The size it attains
by the time we return
will give us an exact growth
rate to expect of the herds.
How much are you getting paid,
phil? Mind my asking?
At the rate the gargon
is expected to grow,
what will prevent it
from tearing loose
the leg bands and escaping
from the cave?
Shut up, gomer.
We shall be back
before that happens,
unless it should receive
food in excess of the
atmospheric elements.
We will leave nothing else
for it to consume.
Oh, you've really relieved me.
Thanks loads.
Imagine...thousands
of beasts like that.
Keep me moist!
I should be in water!
Millions of times enlarged,
roaming over this planet.
They will be harvested
from the air,
so there will be
no danger to us.
Let us be quick.
I do not like to look upon it.
Let us implement
contractions.
♪♪
Boo!
Now that you report the planet
is suitable for our purposes,
you are to return here
immediately
and prepare to lead the
transport ships there.
But, sir,
you're a hand puppet.
Derek's escape
could now mean difficulty
in our operation,
should he communicate
in any way with the inhabitants,
inferior though they may be.
If we are to return now,
how can he be stopped?
Over!
Leave your best man
to find derek
and inform him he is my son.
I will join you on the return
trip to meet him there.
He may be stubborn.
He has already
threatened our lives.
If that becomes the case,
he-- he must be destroyed.
What about torture?
And any beings with whom he
might communicate,
they must be destroyed.
Your orders are complete.
Oh, wow.
I shall send my best man.
Oh, oh.
[Clears throat]
[Whistles a tune]
Nothing, nothing.
I heard the orders,
captain.
Let me...
Entertain you!
Find derek.
You will wait until
the sky is light enough
to begin the search.
It is light!
We will leave now and return
here to meet you when
we bring the gargons.
[Crows squawking]
Hmm?
Go back to your planet,
space teens!
Do not fail, thor.
I shall not fail.
♪♪
You'll fail!
You cannot beat us!
We're the people!
We'll poop on you!
Run your fastest!
Jump your highest!
Look at that stupid jumpsuit,
belted at the waist.
Uh, yours is nice.
The loneliness
of the alien runner.
♪♪
Life is simple here
in grover's corner.
♪♪
♪ doo doo doo doo doo ♪
gee, davey.
♪ Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
♪♪
♪ doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
♪ doo doo doo doo
doo doo doo ♪
♪ doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
Aah!
Oh, don't do that.
Are you my daddy?
♪ Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
Jim henson's
beretta babies.
♪♪
Let's watch
as an alien visits
one of our friendly
texaco stations.
♪ Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
Can I help you, sir?
Yes, I...
Fill her up, please.
Would--
would you tell me
the meaning
of the inscription
on this metal piece?
What do I look like,
the shell answer man?
Oh, oh, that's right,
I am.
"Sparky,
1243 willowcrest drive."
That's just three blocks down
there and a few doors up.
You can't miss it.
Hmm?
Damn illegal aliens.
Hey, watch what
you're doing there.
[Gasps]
Sorry, senator helms.
I was just trying to make out
what kind of clothes that guy
was wearing.
Looks like some kind of
military uniform.
Wonder where he's from.
Could be from mars,
for all I care.
Hurry up there, boy, will ya?
I haven't got all day.
Light a cigar, buddy.
♪♪
Oh, no, he forgot to ask the
other person what a block was.
♪♪
Hmm?
Excuse me, is that
a zandveld jumpsuit?
Hop in,
I'll give you a lift.
Lift?
Well, it's a long way
into town.
Town?
Okay, it's all right
with me if--
wait!
It's vince sutton.
It's sergeant carter!
♪♪
I'm looking for
sarah connor.
They're scooched, right?
Never saw a uniform
like that before.
What brings you here?
The sugar beet festival.
And you?
I am searching for someone.
Maybe I can help you.
Know a lot of folks
around these parts.
I am searching for someone
you could not know.
Oh, a riddle, huh?
One of them funny
word puzzle jokes.
I like them.
Levittown,
community of the future.
This looks like a nice place
to bring your kids up.
♪♪
♪ doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
"Room for rent."
I put sparky's breakfast out
20 minutes ago, grandpa,
and it's still here.
Probably still out
chasing gophers.
Sweet winona!
Hello.
[Wolf whistle]
You've come to see
our room for rent?
[Grandpa]
What's that?
A fellow to see
the room for rent, grandpa.
You show it him, will you?
Joe will be by for me
in a minute.
We're going swimming
at alice's, and I haven't
even changed yet.
Whoa!
Wait, I just came to say
I killed your dog.
You're harry connick,
aren't you?
Hey.
I'm betty morgan,
and this is my grandfather.
How do you do, son?
Pull my finger. Ha ha!
You can't--I'm kidding.
Just arrived in town?
Don't believe I've seen you
around before.
I just arrived.
And your name?
- Derek.
Mm-hmm.
The empty room belonged
to my brother bud.
He's married now
and lives upstate.
Your brother?
You knew your brother?
Did I know my brother?
That's a strange
question to ask.
Grandpa raised us both
since we were kids after
mom and dad died.
I'm sorry, i--
it's just that I never
knew any brothers or sisters.
[Chuckles]
Your mother and father
decided to play it smart
and avoid a lot of squabbles
around the house.
Oh, grandpa.
I never knew
my mother or father.
Oh, boo hoo. Look,
I've got problems too.
Well, let's take
a look at the room,
and if you like it,
you're welcome to stay.
It's this way--
I'll show it to you.
Hey, I thought you were getting
ready to go swimming.
Oh, that can wait.
Now that teen dream's
here.
There are plenty of windows.
[Chuckles]
Kill them.
♪♪
What's the matter?
You act like you've
never seen the inside
of an automobile before.
What is this?
The gear shift.
Where have you been
all your life?
Where have you
been all my life?
Tell me what it is for.
Now, look, mister,
I didn't offer you a ride to
give no driving lesson.
Tell me!
Why do you look like
hoyt axton?
Sure.
I didn't mean anything.
Here's the clutch.
When I push it in,
I change gears.
Low, second, and high.
And to halt the vehicle?
When I want to stop,
I press the brake.
Right here.
And this?
The starter
and ignition switch.
And the fuel,
what does it use?
Are you kidding?
Gasoline, of course.
Of course.
Here's the gas pedal
right here.
You know,
for all its pitfalls,
this movie educates
as well as entertains.
Hmm.
Did you ever think
about that?
♪♪
You know, joel,
that old grandpa guy
was way too nice
when he rented that room
to the teenager
from outer space.
A real-life landlord
would never be like that.
Why, yes, things that
happen in the movies
are different from the way
they happen in real life.
Right, tom, so here from
our look at the lighter side
department,
we'd like to introduce a new
segment called reel to real.
Let's check it out.
Move aside, you guys.
You see--
there it is.
See, in reel life...
Well, you're offered
free room and board
until you can get a job
and pay back your rent.
In real life...
If you're late with your rent,
your room is padlocked
and you end up living
in a refrigerator box.
In reel life...
Your roommate is
a beautiful young woman
who fills your life
with afternoon swims,
moonlit drives,
and the promise of romance.
In real life...
Your roommate is a stinky
high school dropout
who fills your life
with head lice,
crusty laundry, and furry
cans of spaghetti-os.
In reel life...
Your landlord is a rosy-cheeked,
cheerful old man.
In real life...
Your landlord's
a butane addict who sneaks
into your apartment
and looks through
your underwear drawer.
In reel life...
There's a big, fat, drunk guy
sleeping on your couch.
And in real life...
There's a big, fat, drunk guy
sleeping on your couch.
[Laughter]
These are just a few
of the differences
in real life and reel life.
Stay with us on our look on
the lighter side department
for some of those
everyday befuddlements
that come at us in such
a humorous way.
Like dieting.
I just look at a piece of bread
and I gain five pounds.
Look at crow here-- he can
eat ten banana splits
and not gain an ounce.
I hate him!
And mondays--
what are you gonna do?
Don't even talk to me
till I've had my coffee
in the morning.
What about starting the car.
Have you thought about it?
My hip hurts. Why?
♪♪
It's not right.
Oh, what's he reading?
Prostrate world news?
That'd be "prostate."
I asked him where
he was from, grandpa,
and he just said
he was from very far away.
A british village, maybe.
Well, maybe he doesn't like to
talk about where he's from.
By the looks of his outfit,
I'd say he was raised in a
private school of some sort.
He must go to that parochial
school down the road.
Well, grandpa,
if he just got into town
and can't pay the rent
until he gets a job
or something, would--
well, what do you say,
young man?
What do you think
of the room?
Tough room, huh?
You will let me...
Live here with you?
Well, sure. That's why
we have the sign up.
That's why you came here,
wasn't it?
[Clears throat]
Not exactly, i--
jeepers, this dog tag's
a gold mine.
Derek, I was just
talking to grandpa, and,
well, if you don't have
the rent money right away,
that could wait until
he gets a job,
couldn't it, grandpa?
Mm, why, sure.
That's all right with me, betty.
Sucker!
But then, if he doesn't
like the room...
I like it here.
Very much.
Yes, thank you.
I would like to stay.
Fine. I'll go out and
take down the sign.
You can use the phone to have
your bags brought over.
You have a bellboy too?
My bags?
I have nothing else.
No other clothes
or anything?
We were not allowed to--
I mean, my uniform
is all I have.
Gosh, you've gotta
have more than that.
Bud left some of his clothes in
the closet, grandpa.
Couldn't derek
use some of them?
Well, of course, my dear.
Bud wouldn't mind
a bit, I'm sure.
[Car horn honks]
Oh, golly, that's joe.
He's from venus.
Put on whatever you like from
the closet, derek.
I'll be right back--
make yourself at home.
Just stay out
of my clothes.
Hi there, joe.
Hi, gramps.
Betty, I 'm afraid I can't make
the swimming date.
Not till later, anyway.
Got a sudden assignment
for the paper.
Oh, gosh, what now, joe?
I have a list of folks to
interview.
Say they saw a new
flying saucer last night.
That sounds like it might take
you all day.
I hope not.
I'll call you as soon
as I get through, okay?
Okay, joe.
Why don't you ask
the alien who's staying
with you about this?
Ah, I guess a reporter's life
can be pretty hectic.
You never know when
a news story will break.
I was just thinking...
Maybe derek would
like to go swimming,
if you'd let us
borrow the car.
Bet he would at that.
Uh, if you don't
think alice would mind.
[Laughs]
You don't know alice.
I won't be able to
keep them apart.
[Knocking]
Hey, let me out!
[Muffled shouting]
[Laughs]
[Crying]
Stay calm,
uh, act natural.
Uh, can I interest you in
a texaco christmas album?
[Laughs]
♪♪
Hey, what's going on in town
anyway, mister?
Convention or something?
What?
Well, those clothes
you're wearing.
I talked to a guy this
morning who was wearing
the same kind of outfit.
May be the guy
you're looking for, huh?
You spoke to him?
What did he tell you?
Where did he go?
Hey, what's the matter
with you?
Hey, take your hands
off me.
You will tell me
what he said to you!
Why should I?
Hey, who do you think
you are, anyway?
Answer me,
or I destroy you!
He came here with a dog tag.
Wanted to know about the
address, and I told him
how to find it.
Where...
Where did you send him?
It was an address
on willowcrest drive.
Tell me how to get there.
Just drive down there
about three blocks.
That's--
that's willowcrest.
1243,
it's only a few doors up.
Uh-oh.
[Droning]
Whoa, it's like
a jenny craig ray.
Wow.
Somebody help!
[Droning]
Well, guess it's
a self-serve now, huh?
Come on, baby, out, out.
I'll drive now.
[Bones rattling]
Rattle them bones.
Mm-hmm.
[Tires screech]
You don't have to put the brake
on so hard, derek.
That is, unless you
want us to go through
the windshield every time.
I have never piloted
a vehicle like this before.
I will try again.
This time, pull in there.
That's alice's house.
Xanadu, stately home
of charles foster kane.
Cost?
No one can say.
Ah, much better.
Wait, betty.
Uh, you have toilet
paper on your shoe.
Yes, derek, what is it?
When I came to your place,
it was because of...
Uh, I'm all mixed up
inside.
Yes?
I had just arrived here.
I-- I did not know
where else to go,
but everything was
so strange to me, I...
Oh, that's great.
Can we just go in the house?
I'm glad you came.
So's grandpa.
"Sgrandpa"?
Without any family
or friends,
you wouldn't like it at a hotel
or any place like that.
Come on.
I hope alice can dig up some
swim trunks for you.
Uh, I have never piloted
swim trunks before.
♪♪
Operator, there's a naked girl
in my pool and she's nude!
[Laughs]
Hi there!
Likewise, I'm sure.
Who's the stranger?
Joe couldn't make it, alice.
I talked derek into coming
along.
Derek, this is alice.
Derek!
Hey, I like that.
Come on in,
the water's fine.
And so am I.
Well, we need a pair
of swim trunks.
I couldn't find any
at my house.
No problem at all.
He can wear a pair
of my father's.
They've got
the support panel.
The folks are gone today,
and so are the servants.
We have the whole place to
ourselves.
Mmmmmm...
Where are the trunks,
alice?
Hanging up,
right over there.
Earth girls are easy.
They look a little large
for you, derek.
Maybe you better put them on
with some clothespins,
too, just in case.
Ooh, she makes everything
sound so dirty.
I guess it's safe to
try 'em on anyway.
Over there,
at the bathhouse.
[Dog tag bounces]
What was that?
Don't worry, I'll get it.
Probably just
a silly old plot point.
It was what I wanted
to tell you about,
the reason I came to your
place when I did not know
where else to go.
Heck, I thought it was
a 50-cent piece at least.
[Singsong]
Derek killed your dog,
derek killed your dog.
Well, it is.
That's sparky's.
Sparky's dog tag.
Where on earth
did you find it?
Well, after caving in
his head with a shovel...
When I first arrived,
I was with some others.
One of them destroyed
a small creature.
Later, I found that
among the remains.
You mean,
somebody killed sparky?
Mm-hmm.
Oh no, derek,
it can't be true.
Why would anyone
want to kill sparky?
'Cause he was a schnauzer.
I hate those things.
[Alice]
Betty, I'm sorry.
Tell me who did it, derek.
They...
Are gone now.
Only I remain.
But...i don't understand.
Where is spark--
ky.
Sparky.
Will you take me
to where it happened?
I'll get dressed
and come with you.
No, alice, please.
Don't get dressed.
You stay here.
We'll see you later.
♪♪
Hmm.
♪ It's the new zoo revue
coming right at you ♪
[Muffled shouting]
Come on, man!
Let me out!
[Muffled shouting]
Well, well, so derek
didn't come into town alone.
If you're looking for him,
he isn't here now.
He and betty-- that's my
granddaughter--
they went over
to the woodwards.
Why don't you go on
over there?
No doubt they'd be glad to have
you join in the fun.
Yes.
How do I go there?
Let me count the ways.
The woodwards are straight
on down the street
about three miles, just before
you get to the park.
Got the biggest house
on the block down there.
You can't miss it.
Just like you
can't miss me.
Where you fellas from,
anyway?
Don't believe I've seen
uniforms like yours before.
I like you, gramps.
That's why I kill you last.
Hmm, military secret, eh?
Heh heh.
Well, it doesn't matter.
Derek didn't say
where he's from either.
Have you met
my granddaughter?
Don't let me keep you.
You're probably
anxious to see him.
Don't leave your dog
in the car on a hot day!
[Humming]
[Sniffing]
Woof!
Sparky!
[Whistling]
Here, sparky!
Sparks! Sparks!
[Whistling]
Here, boy, here, boy.
Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
Where is he, derek?
Yecchh!
You don't mean
those old bones.
You can see they've been here
for a very long time.
No. It was among these remains
that I found the metal
inscription.
This couldn't be sparky.
Sparky had skin.
I know-- he must have been here,
and his collar tag fell off.
That's all.
Hey, wake up and smell
the collie.
You are not familiar
with the focusing
disintegrator ray?
Yeah, my aunt has one.
The what?
It projects an isolated beam
which separates the molecules
of living material
in chain reaction.
It slices, it dices.
All but the solids,
the skeletal braces.
How horrible.
Yet effective.
And you mean sparky...
But--
over there is what happened
when the same beam
was aimed at me.
It missed, and...
Became a tree.
That is what is left.
Good heavens, derek.
You've got to
explain it to me.
Why were they doing this?
Where were they from?
How did you--
and who took the frames
out of the film?
♪♪
[Imitates dog panting]
Hello, uhura.
Well, hello.
At ease, soldier.
What can I do for you?
You are alone?
Could be.
Where are the others?
The ones who were with you.
Why do you want to know that?
Tell me where they are.
Miss hathaway,
the early years.
Say, who are you anyway?
Never mind!
Just tell me.
They left here...
They're gone.
Where did they go?
I think you better get out of
here before I call the police.
You will call no one.
You will do as I say.
That's what you think,
mister.
Look, pat boone
is the stand-in here.
This is bogus!
I'm going to the deep end!
I said you
will call no one!
[Droning]
Too much chlorine!
Yes, folks, proof you can
be too rich and too thin.
Hey, she just changed
into the same dress.
Huh?
Who decorated this house,
wayland flowers?
Darn corns.
Ooh, ooh.
♪♪
Eh, gramps started
early today.
Oh, grandpa, I bought
that nyquil for colds,
not for you
to make nyquiladas.
"Dear gramps, I cannot
continue to live this way."
And the post-it note
was born.
♪♪
Grandpa, I left a note
for you by the phone for
when you wake up.
Grandpa!
Who's putting spiders
all over my... oh.
It's gramps.
He's got the flu again.
Grandpa was asleep,
so I left a note so he'll
know where we went.
If I know grandpa,
we'll be back before
he even wakes up.
If he ever wakes up.
[Muffled shouting]
[Phone ringing]
Still getting...
[Mumbling]
Oh, ah, ah!
♪ It's the new zoo revue ♪
♪ coming back at you ♪
♪ it's quite
an amazing thing ♪
♪ when the animals... ♪
[Yawns] Hello?
Hello, gramps?
This is joe-- betty there?
No, she and derek went on over
to the woodwards' pool.
You can probably
reach her over there.
Derek-- who's derek?
Oh, you haven't met him yet,
have you?
He's betty's new regular
saturday night thing.
Yeah, he rented bud's
old room this morning.
Seems like a nice fellow.
Oh?
At first.
Well, the reason I called,
I wanted to tell betty
I stumbled onto
a double murder story
that may keep me longer,
but, well,
after I get the story
into the paper,
I'll go on over to alice's
and see her there.
A double murder, joe?
When was it, where?
We're not sure yet, gramps.
There's only a couple of
skeletons.
And they're not talking.
We'll know more
when the coroner gets here.
Well, gotta get busy now,
gramps. I'll talk to you
later-- bye!
Oh, you don't need
to see that, no.
Joe! Joe, I just
found a note. Joe--
what do you know?
Hello, hello!
Hello, joe,
what do you know?
Just got back from kokomo.
[Muffled shouting]
I got it-- he looks like,
uh, ethel waters.
Yeah.
[Muffled shouting]
By golly, you missed them
at the pool, huh?
On a killing spree, huh?
Sure am sorry.
Uh, betty left me a note.
Now they've gone over
to the college
to see professor simpson.
Give me that.
Hey, room 222.
Yeah.
[Whistling a tune]
You know, school always smells
the same when you go back.
Mm-hmm.
Yep.
It smells like shame,
guilt, and humiliation.
Hey, sylvia plath!
Hello. Where can we find
professor simpson?
This is his office, but he
hasn't come in yet.
It's barbie's
malibu dream desk.
Let's wait for him in the
faculty parking lot.
It's just around
the building.
You may wait here
if you like.
No, thank you.
We'll wait outside.
Your desk embarrasses us.
Tiny.
Now I'll show you
my old locker.
I wonder if I still
remember the combination.
♪ Doo doo doo,
come on ♪
♪ it's a nice day
for a white wedding ♪
♪ doo doo doo,
nice day ♪
♪ ooh, doo doo,
to start again ♪
Uh, miss hathaway, jethro
wants to be a rock star.
Good morning, hilda.
Oh, good morning,
professor simpson.
Ooph!
Uh, call
the burn ward pronto.
Have the aptitude
questionnaires come in?
They're probably still in
mimeographing.
I'll go down and see
if they're ready.
Poor guy.
[Singing]
That's professor simpson's
office.
The third door down.
He's head of the science
department.
Yeah, if you throw up
or need some sawdust,
just call me.
[Muffled shouting]
Well, that looks like
professor simpson's car
right there.
He must be
somewhere else on campus.
We'd better go back
to his office and wait.
Hello, this is simpson,
science department.
Put that down.
What is the meaning
of this?
Do as I say.
Who are you?
Where is he?
The one who came with
information for you.
Who? You are making
some mistake.
I am making no mistake.
Where did he go--
out there?
I don't know
what you're talking about!
You will speak
to no one else.
[Droning]
♪♪
That raygun works well,
but you can't get
the stink out of it.
Ooph! Never toasted somebody
that old before.
Ahh!
Ooph! Smells like
the primate house in here.
Jeepers!
[Grunting]
Went a little. Huh.
♪♪
♪ she was a fast machine,
she kept her motor clean ♪
We found his car, so--
[chuckles]
Yes, I know.
He came in
right after you left.
♪♪
Hold my calls, will you?
Ha ha!
[Screams]
I'll be taking lunch,
hilda.
Oh, derek.
Oh, it's some kind
of foolish joke.
I'm not going to keep
a job where this sort
of thing goes on.
Is that the straw that
broke the camel's back?
Yep.
I want to believe what i'm
thinking isn't true, but--
it was
a focusing disintegrator.
Then whoever killed sparky...
Used a focusing
disintegrator.
But you said they'd gone!
For some reason,
they want to stop me.
Somehow,
we were traced here.
I want you to get in
your vehicle
and go to a place
where you will be safe.
But how could they--
[gasps]
Grandpa!
What?
I left a note for grandpa.
They must have--
oh, derek!
Grandpa squealed!
I will go to your place.
No, they may be
waiting for you there.
I can call grandpa.
Here, grandpa!
[Whistling]
Here, boy.
Here, grandpa.
♪♪
Hey, room for one, buddy.
[Phone ringing]
Oh, goody,
somebody needs a room.
Hello?
Oh, grandpa, thank heavens.
Derek, he's all right.
Betty, what is it, child?
What's the matter?
Grandpa, was somebody there?
Somebody you told
we were at the college?
Oh, yes.
The friend of derek's.
Did he find you okay?
He's a murderer!
He killed professor simpson,
grandpa!
He's after derek, and he's
probably on the way back
to the house right now.
But does he need a room?
A murderer?
But are the police--
don't argue, grandpa.
Just get out of there.
This call is coming
from inside the house!
We're going to the city hall
police station right now.
Meet us there.
Don't worry about me, betty.
I'll leave right away.
I'll pack a bag of trusses
and be out in a minute.
Good-bye, honey.
Aah!
[Muffled shouting]
I better call
the police and let them
know we're coming.
Nickels,
check for nickels!
With what weapons are they
equipped?
With guns, why?
Guns that emit what?
Love! Why?
Bullets.
What do you mean?
Bullets. Centuries-old
invention against--
hello, operator?
Give me the police
department, hurry.
Nobody expects
the spanish inquisition!
Mixed weaponry, uh,
figure it's a surprise.
Wow, this is pretty nice.
I don't think I want to
destroy this house after all.
Boy, it sure
is a nice place.
A guy could really
rent a room here.
Hmm, hmm.
Sure would like to rent
one of these rooms.
♪ Ooh doo doo doo ♪
♪♪
Yes, we'll be there
right away.
Thank you.
Betty, tell me
how to go there.
I want you to go somewhere else
where you will be safe.
Where's safer
than the city hall?
The police said they're
going to have armed guards
waiting for us
on the front steps.
I told them
we'd be right there.
Let's hurry.
They're scurrying!
♪ I thinking
it's the new zoo revue ♪
♪ coming after you ♪
Oh, ho ho ho ho!
♪♪
All right, you guys,
the waste receptacle's
in position.
Are you ready?
Roger!
Okay, I'm about to
jettison the snacks
into space!
Oh, boy, here they go.
[Imitates rapid firing]
♪ Dah dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah ♪
♪ dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah dah ♪
♪ dah dah dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah ♪
♪ dah dah dah dah
♪ dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah dah ♪
♪ dah dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah ♪
♪ dah dah dah dah dah dah
dahhhhh ♪
♪ dah dah dah dah ♪
There is no smoking
in this auditorium.
♪ Dah dah dah dah
dah dah dah dah ♪
And now we invite you
to enjoy our feature
presentation...
♪ Tah dah ♪
♪ dah ♪
[Overlapping shouting]
[Mechanical whirring]
♪ Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo doo ♪
[Laughs]
Alien crossing.
♪♪
Wow, he's gonna turn
city hall into the museum
of natural history.
Ooh!
I guess you can fight
city hall.
There you go.
Snap, crackle,
pop, rico, lee!
[Droning]
♪˯ doo doo doo ♪
Watch out, or he'll
turn you into a dead head.
Whoa, oh!
Uhh!
Only a flesh wound.
Too late.
[Gunshots]
[Droning]
Ah, I'm hit! I'm hit,
charlie, I'm hit!
What's that thing
on his head?
[Gunshots]
Derek, no!
[Groans]
Oh, they're using
real bullets, those bastards!
♪♪
Cover me.
[Laughs]
♪♪
Well.
Well, that was fun.
Now, where were we?
Should we chase them
or knock off for coffee?
What do you think?
He must have slipped off
that way-- come on.
Go hang bob
in my office.
Stay under cover.
♪ Undercover angel ♪
♪ midnight... ♪
♪♪
Hey, scoop!
Hi, they went that-a-way.
Jimmy olsen here.
Betty!
Thank the lord you're safe.
I just came from alice's.
There was a skeleton
in the pool, i--
alice?
Oh, no!
We came to meet grandpa.
A lot of grief.
The murderer came
in the car with him.
What?
But how did you
get mixed up in this?
We think they killed
sparky out by the old mine.
She sounds like betty boop
all of a sudden.
He's an insane killer, joe!
And he forced gramps
to drive here?
Where is gramps--
is he okay?
Yes, he's-- well, there
he is, trying to get
across the street.
Stay, grandpa, stay!
You stay put.
I'll go over
and help him across.
♪♪
That's the last
boy scout.
♪ I have often walked
down this street before ♪
♪ but I've never done it
packing heat before ♪
[Laughs]
♪♪
Hey.
What are you
doing down here?
Go into the building.
That is the safest place.
Hmm?
Look, look.
Look.
Pick a cup of sauce.
Here on the sidewalk.
Drops of blood.
Betty,
go into the building.
One at a time,
ding-ding-ding.
Derek...
Surprise!
Give me the weapon
you have, derek.
Hey, it's a tube of crest.
He must be a cavity fighter.
One sudden move,
and I slay you both!
I'll try to control you!
Derek, do as he says.
What?
Nice luger.
Get in!
Okay, okay,
I'm getting in!
Jeez, what a grouch.
You will take me
to a man of surgery
to remove the metal
pellets from my flesh.
That is not possible.
Well, it's 2:30.
They're probably all golfing.
We must do as he says.
I know a doctor's office.
We'll take him there.
She is very wise.
Oh, you like her?
Now go!
Hey, and a want
a jolly rancher fire stick
when I'm done, too.
♪♪
Watch your space cushion.
Slow, slow. I don't--oh.
And that's the way
it happened.
I'm walter cronkite.
Next thing I knew,
he was trying to fire out the
window at betty and derek.
He's talking
to clifford irving.
I swerved the car and--
say, where is betty?
Where is betty?
That's funny. She must be
around someplace.
But the car is gone.
They must have left
without me.
Get the hint, gramps?
Well, don't worry, gramps.
You'll get an escort home.
I'm going to phone
the story in to the paper
and then drive out to the old
mine betty mentioned.
The old mine?
What's out there?
I don't know.
That's where she said sparky
was killed by the guy.
How come I always have to
do the expositions?
Sparky, our dog?
She didn't tell me
about that.
Hey, mac, over here!
Blood spots
on the sidewalk.
A car has been
bleeding here.
And where's that car
that was parked here?
That's it. That's how
the killer got away.
In our car?
Then betty and derek,
they must have been kidnapped!
You've got to do something!
You've got to find them.
D'oh.
♪ Hot child in the city ♪
This is it, derek.
That's dr. Brandt there.
He looks like he's leaving.
Stop him-- block his path!
♪♪
♪ lookin' good
and feelin' pretty ♪
[Tires screech]
Hey, you blocked
my path!
Is there some emergency?
I have a house call
to make.
Office hours don't
begin for another hour.
[Thor]
Go inside, all of you!
I say, what is this?
And you say it
rather woodenly.
He's holding a gun
on us, dr. Brandt.
We had to bring him here.
Oh, I see it now.
He wants bullets removed.
I see.
Well, I don't see, but...
I'm afraid
I cannot be of any help.
You will need hospital
facilities for anything--
be silent and get inside!
You will remove the pellets
here, now.
Leave these people
alone, thor.
He's so gentle.
Where is our ship?
I will take you there.
No, it is gone.
Do as I say!
Derek, please.
Doctor, you must try.
Hmm...hmm...
Ah, criminy, come on, dummy.
I was going to a hat party.
Mine was the grandest
of all, too.
Big feather boa
in the back, too.
♪♪
Now, you'll have to
wait an hour.
It's standard procedure.
♪♪
Ah, sorry about the mess.
This kind of doubles
as my room.
I've just got to clean
a few things up here.
You will have to
lie down here.
I will prepare an anesthetic.
The pain will be great.
I will not be drugged.
You will simply
remove the pellets.
Well, I won't be
using this then.
Both of you, sit there.
I shall keep you covered.
I did not say,
"simon says."
Take heed. One treacherous
move, and they pay with
their lives.
Now proceed.
In iambic pentameter.
Shall I compare thee
to a fleshy wound?
Hey, what's a turkey roasting
pan doing in the office?
I don't know.
If he dies,
they can make soup.
Hey, you're put together
all differently.
You're a willowy young thing,
aren't you?
♪♪
He likes that.
Oh, looks like your
popper's come up. Oh,
that's your nipple.
Thor...
Yeth, it is very thor.
Tell me why you have been
searching for me.
It must have been important
for you to have--
the gargon
had to be raised here.
Oh, yeah, the lobsters.
I forgot.
You could not be
allowed to run free.
But the specimen
reaction was negative.
It was verified positive
after you escaped.
The captain should have
let me kill you
when I had the chance!
And why didn't he?
I saw him stop you when you
fired at me.
Because--
he likes the cut
of your jib.
Because he just learned
that--
that you are
the son of our leader.
I'm david eisenhower.
That makes you
julie nixon!
♪♪
Huh, a cigarette butt.
What the hell is that
doing in there?
♪♪
Suddenly it's
carnival of souls.
♪♪
[Gasps]
Look!
Oh, oh, come on,
come on.
Yes, yes, yes, come on,
baby, come on.
Come on, oh, oh, oh, uh,
aw.
Then if I am
not to be killed,
why did you fire at me
in the city?
Your life or death
was put in my hands.
A traitor does not deserve
to be our next leader!
The only reason
you do not fire now
is to force attention
to your wounds.
When that is done...
Proceed!
Oh, okay,
let's see here.
Remove funny bone.
Ha ha ha.
Well, here's the little
bugger that was causing
all the trouble.
♪♪
Okay, hop down.
Put your clothes on.
Antiseptic must be
applied to your wounds,
and you will need bandages.
I recommend sea breeze
astringent.
♪♪
Hmm, no insurance.
Sad, really.
♪ Hot blooded,
check it and see ♪
♪♪
[Groaning]
Auntie em, uncle henry,
you were there
and you and you and you...
♪♪
Yeah, all right.
Yes!
Oh!
Where was I on the night
of the 14th?
♪♪
Come back!
I--I'll find you.
It's bryan ferry!
Love is the drug for him!
[Grunting]
[Weakly]
You're in here.
I know you are.
But what am I?
I'll find you!
And then you'll be it!
Hmm.
[Brakes screech]
All right, this is
your stop, grandpa.
Out, baby--
out, out, out!
♪♪
My nurse, miss morse!
She'll be arriving
for office hours.
Boy, the old guy moves
when he wants to.
Yeah, good truss on him.
[Panting]
Uhh!
Got to solve the jumble!
I can hear you!
Tommy, I can hear you.
I can feel you near me.
You--you cannot escape me!
I'm charles foster kane!
I'll find you,
I'll find you!
There you are--you're
in a sailboat over the--
uhh!
Oh, here comes
the s.S. Nurse.
♪˯ ga-ding-a-ding a-ding-ding,
ding-a-ding a-ding ♪
♪˯ ding-a-ding a-ding
ding ding ♪
Here we go, folks.
♪♪
♪ yes, I'm a sex shooter ♪
♪ shooting love
in your direction ♪
[Humming]
Hmm?
What?
Oh, the doctor left
another young one
bleeding on the stoop
again.
Ah!
Have you been
waiting long, hmm?
Dr. Brandt!
There's a dead spaceman
to see you, sir.
♪♪
♪ doo doo doo doo doo ♪
♪ snot is running down
your... ♪
She's already left?
Okay, good-bye, then.
Uhh!
Not very courteous.
Hmm, wesson oil
on a wound?
Yeah, she's not
florence nightingale,
she's florence henderson.
Oh!
[Phone ringing]
Oh, every time
I'm about to swab.
[Ringing continues]
♪ Picture yourself
on a train in the station ♪
♪ mmmm mmmm mmm ♪
♪ and marshmallows
and mmmm ♪
♪˯ I don't give a damn,
the next step is vietnam ♪
Hmm?
[Ringing continues]
Hmm.
It must be that nice
adam rich boy
calling for his
prescription again.
[Ringing]
♪ Hey doo doo doo oh ♪
Dr. Brandt's office.
Miss morse, thank heavens
I've reached you.
This is dr. Brandt.
Where are you, doctor?
There's an emergency
patient here.
I've done all I can--
listen, miss morse,
he's a murderer.
'Cause pepperidge farm
remembers.
He held hostages at gunpoint to
force me to remove bullets.
We were fortunate in escaping.
You must get out of there.
A "mordewer"?
No, I said murderer!
If you've treated him,
he could revive at any moment.
Y-Yes, doctor.
I'll leave immediately.
You will come with me.
Put that down!
Miss morse, miss morse,
what is it?
He doesn't have
any insurance!
And don't lift a finger!
What do you want?
You will help me to escape.
Go out!
Wait a minute!
Miss morse!
Just leave your bones
by the door!
Miss morse!
♪♪
Nobody else pull a raygun.
You put that right away.
That vehicle.
Is that how you arrived?
Yes, that's my car.
In style.
Get in. You will take me
where I say.
If you disobey,
you will be killed!
I hope your bandages
stick to your scabs,
you son of a...
The police are on the way,
dr. Brandt. They--
it's no use.
I was too late.
They're gone.
I wasn't
the fifth caller.
Thor has escaped?
But how could he?
You said he would be
helpless, that--
without aid, but my nurse,
she didn't know.
She bandaged him,
gave him an injection.
He revived.
Oh, no.
Then they played
jimi hendrix.
All day at black rock,
eh?
Well, we've got to tell
the police. They might be
able to do something.
I'll tell them.
No, no,
that would be telling.
I'll tell them
what happened.
Ladies and gentlemen,
charles schultz
premiering peanuts.
♪♪
Who are you again?
Oh, my girlfriend.
Okay.
Oh, have I got
a nervous tummy.
The thinker.
Don't worry, derek.
Thor will be caught.
They're sure to find him
eventually.
It is what I know
is coming here.
Lend me a tenner?
The gargon.
They are small
when young...
But they'll claw ya.
But they can attain the--
the size of this building
in no more than a day.
But can't you stop them?
Only if they're willing
to stop themselves.
The only chance
is to duplicate
the operation
of the disintegrator.
We'll need a shoestring
and a picture of eve arden.
How can that be done?
The men of science here
might be able to do it
if they could get
thor's as a model.
If only there is
enough time.
You know,
this little dog has become
quite a tourist attraction
around here.
Ah, yup.
Arf.
You know,
I don't get this guy.
It's not a guy,
it's a dog.
Animals or humans,
he just seems to like killing.
There's more to it
than that, joe.
There's something
behind this.
Something
we don't understand.
Like the new math.
The weapon he uses,
it's unheard of.
Blasting flesh
right off the bones.
Really a waste.
Look at that tree
over there.
Used it for target practice,
by the looks of it.
Ah, that's pretty
far-fetched, bob.
I don't know.
Let's take a look
in the old cave.
♪♪
♪ row, row, row ♪
come on, sing!
♪ Row, row,
row your boat ♪
Where are we going?
You've got to tell me.
So I know
where to turn.
It is not far now.
You can't escape.
The police will find you.
Possibly they will,
but barricaded
in the mouth of a cave
with you as hostage
and me with this--
how long do you think you can
hold out that way?
Long enough.
There will not be
too long to wait.
Suspicion, north by--
ah, you know.
Why do you seek the living
among the dead?
Hey, bring your
flashbulbs up here.
This tunnel
is black as pitch.
Okay, I'll be right up.
And it's filled
with chili.
It's a tunnel of chili,
like a hormel hot dog.
Get it?
[Mac screaming,
gargon wailing]
[Bones crunching]
Should I bring
more flashbulbs?
Mac!
♪♪
Uh-oh.
An intruder already!
No!
I won't let you
kill anyone.
You'll kill someone
over my dead body!
I see you do not
value your life!
Much!
He's getting away!
Follow him!
No!
You dare refuse?
Hey, hey, that's where
I draw the line!
Pistol whipping.
♪♪
Damn, the tree.
I hate that!
♪♪
After him, scoob!
That reporter's running
away from the story.
♪♪
Kind of like the year of
living sensibly, you know?
♪♪
You don't see this shot in
movies very often, do you?
No, uh-- mm-hmm.
No, this is
just like misery.
What do you mean?
This is misery.
I'll say.
San diego freeway,
the early years.
Menopause can feel like
a speeding car chase.
[Moaning]
I've got a headache this big,
and it's got this movie
written all over it.
Whoa, he shouldn't be driving
without corrective lenses.
Aah!
Oh!
It's mae "the super nurse"
osborne.
Ooh.
♪♪
♪ doo doo doo doo
doo doo ♪
♪ doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
Ah, what do you know?
"Valley" parking.
♪♪
How'd I do that?
Ooph!
Those easy spirit pumps
saved her hash.
♪♪
Well, she's fine, but these
stains will never come out.
Are you hurt badly?
Well, i--
I don't think so.
Well, then,
down hill with you!
Just bruised.
Oh, thank heavens it's over.
It was like a nightmare.
Only I wasn't aboard
that pirate ship with my--
i-- I wish it was over.
Well, what do you mean?
Back in the cave,
where he shot at me.
Some kind of
man-eating monster.
Poor mac,
the guy I was with.
I could hear the thing
tearing him apart.
It sounded delicious.
He was dead
in a few seconds.
Oh, how horrible.
What could it have been?
I don't know.
But whatever it is,
I'm afraid the nightmare
has just begun.
♪ Da dah dah dunnn ♪
♪♪
Thor crashed
just below here.
If that disintegrator
is down there,
I'm going to find it.
Derek, I just thought...
Well, stop that.
The monster that escaped
from the cave,
it must have been there
at the same time we were.
What I can't figure out is why
did it escape when it did?
Why not sooner?
Why do I love it
like I do?
It would not have been
large enough.
But the man it consumed
increased its growth rate.
Stupid old man.
Then how big
would it be now?
There is no telling.
Have you seen
listomania?
You stay here,
keep the door closed.
Oh, and if a strange looking
lobster comes knocking,
ignore it.
♪♪
[Humming]
Well,
there's the rockford car,
there's the starsky
and hutch car, and--oh.
♪♪
Clothes by
charlie mccarthy.
♪♪
Yep, no.
No easter eggs here.
The hills have crabs.
♪♪
Wait.
I'm getting hot.
Why didn't he crack a window?
♪♪
Derek?
Derek,
can I have the keys
so I can listen
to the radio at least?
♪♪
Ah, queen anne's lace,
morning glories, buttercups.
Hmm.
♪♪
It's andrew wyeth's valley.
No, betty, go back, it's too
dangerous for you--
we can find that thing
twice as fast if we both look.
Oh!
Well, as long
as we're down here...
You make me angry,
but I like you very much.
In a moment, the moon will come
from behind a cloud.
What is this, a bergman film
all of a sudden?
It'll be easier to see what
we're looking for.
Yes.
The light from your moon,
it will help.
My moon?
[Making up words
that sound swedish]
Where are you from, derek?
A place called studsville.
Population: Me.
I think I know.
I think I've known
for some time.
You are one weird
mamma jamma.
You're not from
this world, are you?
You're from the valley,
aren't you?
I did not know
how to tell you.
I'm from jersey.
It seems impossible
to believe.
Believe it or not.
You're so much like us.
Wait until
you see my tongues.
Like my brother, or grandpa,
when he was young.
And had a liver.
And to think...
We were made the same.
How inconvenient.
The only difference is
that we were put on places
far, far apart.
Oh, now he's gonna
sing ebony and ivory.
What is it like...
Where you're from?
Babies are bred
and raised like livestock,
parented by the most perfect
specimens of our race.
Hmm, sounds nice.
If you become ill,
you are put to death...
Hmm, massachusetts,
rhode island.
As are the old.
So they're strict?
Is that what you're saying?
You won't be going back ever,
will you?
I shall make
the earth my home,
and I shall never,
never leave it.
And he'll realize that there
are cuter girls at school.
♪♪
Hmm, ever taste
gargon flesh?
Ever taste
dr. Pepper lip-smacker?
♪♪
Love is cooling
in the sagebrush.
Wocka-wow!
Ooh.
You thought that nurse
had grass stains. Ooph!
The moon has come
from behind the cloud.
Done.
♪♪
Hmm.
Cold.
Getting warmer.
Derek.
The crickets...
We'll name the band
"the crickets."
It's so quiet.
Too quiet.
[Screams]
Oh, my god,
it's my mom!
The gargon-- get back!
There it is, derek!
It was
under the rock-- quick!
[Gargon wailing]
Uh, shrimp in the game.
Shoot it, derek, shoot it!
It won't work-- run!
Go start the motor, hurry!
Hurry!
[Gargon wailing]
For the seafood killer
in you.
Tonight...
It's a rocked lobster!
Whoa, whoa, turn down
the firebird, sweets.
♪♪
Bye, derek!
[Engine starts]
Oops, wrong way.
There you go.
See you, kids.
That's the most terrifying
thing I've ever seen.
And the lobster
was bad too.
Why wouldn't the gun work?
Must have been damaged
somehow when thor was
"flown" in the crash.
"Flown" in the crash?
You said that--that thing
would keep growing.
And the lobster too!
If it does, what can stop it
from wrecking the city and--
I may be able to repair
the damaged part of the
disintegrator.
If I can,
we will stop the gargon
and give the earth a weapon
against invasion as well.
If only
I can get it to work.
Will derek
get it to work?
Tune in next time!
Hey, what does snapper
look like, anyway?
I'm curt gowdy.
Join me and phil harris
as we go after big
texas lobster.
♪♪
Shoot first, seek to
understand later, my friend.
[Distant howl]
What was that?
Only a coyote.
Slammin' sam snead.
There it is!
[Gargon wailing]
[Gunshots]
Oh, that'll happen.
You're bound to lose
a few of your hunting party
right away.
[Gargon wailing]
Oh, no!
He reads too! Aah!
♪♪
Grandpa was so exhausted,
he fell sound asleep
with all his clothes on.
And then he soiled
himself.
Do you think
you can fix it, derek?
I have found
the damaged part.
It's gonna cost you.
Such a little thing.
It's a copper 7.
And yet it has the power to
destroy us, it does.
It is worthless...
Oh, it is a copper 7.
Unless I can figure out
an energy substitute.
Maybe it won't
come into the city, derek.
It will come to the city...
Yeah, it needs
to cash a check.
For more food,
if nothing else.
Well, then I should
set out some snacks.
Meanwhile, at the outhouse
on the hill...
It's mel brooks
in life stinks...
♪♪
Know when to say when--
that's my motto.
Hmm?
This is johnson
at station 86.
Out by the hills,
due northeast,
there's some kind
of a monster!
It suddenly popped up
and seemed to touch the sky!
Ehh!
I have not been drinking!
Hiccupping
no, I can't see it now.
It must be behind the hills.
But I'm getting out of here!
Gah-agg.
♪♪
Come on, old friend.
The few remaining survivors
of the search party that
was attacked
report that the beast they
encountered
was many times
the size they expected,
indicating that the monster
has some strange power
of rapid growth.
An exact description was--
take this.
Come on, take it.
We have a bulletin,
just received.
There's a piece of green
something between your--
according to a report
not yet confirmed,
a beast of seemingly
gigantic proportions
has been sighted lurking
in the hills due
northeast of town.
I don't have
any pants on.
City officials have
called for military help.
Planes and troops are
expected to arrive
within the next two hours.
We gotta roll.
And on the lighter side...
Meanwhile, citizens
should take refuge
in places of safety--
cellars, bomb shelters--
as directed by civil defense
administrators.
I repeat...
[Mechanical whirring]
Is this your card?
Hey, crow, what's up?
Oh, just thinking,
watching the snack food
drift by.
Ah.
Nothing much ever
happens around here.
Black.
It makes me realize
how alone we are.
Know what I mean?
- Black.
- Mm-hmm.
Hanging in space like
a giant speck of food,
floating in the ocean,
sooner or later to be
swallowed up
by some creature
floating by.
Another day in paradise.
Yep, yep, yep.
This is a loaded deck,
isn't it? Black.
I mean, uh, come on,
what if there is no
supreme being?
Wouldn't that be a fine
"how do you do"?
Oh, there's
a supreme being, all right.
Well, okay.
Black.
Hey, tom, what have you
been up to lately?
Red.
Well, you know me.
I try to ward off my
veld schwartz with my hobbies.
- Uh, red.
- Wrong.
Well, I finally finished off
that tristar pegasus logo
we're gonna use
in our next movie pageant.
Oh, really?
That's great.
Yeah, boy, trying to get
those little wings to stick.
Wow, I'd really like to
see that sometime,
you know?
Well, sure, you know,
I've got it right down here.
Hey, guys, there's a ship
coming into view!
Aw, crow,
you're plumb loco.
It's probably just some big
gummi bear from before.
No, no, no,
it's a skull cruiser!
It-- it-- it's black
and demonic, and it spreads
darkness and death.
Cool!
You're so high.
Red.
Gummi bears-- uh,
gummi bears don't spread
darkness and death.
Uh, do they?
And it's piloted
by a ghostly figure
with a dark countenance
and deadly intent!
Yeah, you guys have
gotta see this!
No, I think
you're just seeing
one of those packs
of jordan almonds
we shot out there.
Whoa!
Oh!
Get to rocket number 9
quick!
[Rock music]
♪♪
Boss!
Hooker headers
and thrush pipes,
woofers and tweeters
and bears...
Oh, my!
♪♪
Hey, guys, check out
the hex field view screen.
Wow.
Oh, cool.
Uhh! Uhh! Aah!
Huh? What?
I think he's trying
to tell us something.
[Bones clattering]
Uh...
Oh, man, was that lame!
Boo! Do over!
It seems like
kind of a gyp. Man!
That wasn't cool.
That was the dumbest
visitor ever.
Well, that janitor
was pretty dumb.
Well, that's true.
Well, you know, and the guy
with the thick glasses,
he was--
oh, yeah, yeah--
hey, uh, tom, you know that
pegasus you were working on?
This horse is a cow.
Uh, does it really
make a difference?
I don't think so.
Oh.
We'll be right back.
♪♪
I can help, derek--
I'm going with you.
[Yawning]
What's going on?
What's all
the commotion about?
Grandpa, derek and I are going
out to the edge of town.
Wait for us here.
First I must put the
disintegrator back together
and then find proper tools.
I can load the car with every
tool we have in the garage.
I can load my pants.
All right then, let us go.
Good.
The streets of san francisco--
a quinn martin production.
Epilogue.
♪♪
What the heck?
Before, it was a little town.
Now it's the hollywood hills.
♪♪
I'm not going
in the tunnel.
♪♪
It's sunday morning
in hollywood.
Come on down
to bargain clown!
♪♪
Hey, where'd she go?
Hmm?
♪ Doo doo doo doo ♪
Would you like to go
swimming?
Why aren't you in the cellar,
gramps, with betty?
What makes you think
betty's in the cellar?
She's out somewhere
with derek again.
Everybody
is supposed to take shelter.
The monster from the cave,
it's approaching the town!
Huh? Then that's where
they must have gone.
Those crazy kids.
Joe, we've got to try
and find them.
You mean they--
yes!
Come on, then, let's go!
Come on, joe,
we gotta go, me oh my oh.
♪♪
What is parking?
Teach me of parking.
[Gasps]
Derek, look!
[Gargon wailing]
What, behind
the flying lobster?
♪♪
You drive away.
You can't cut live wires.
Derek, my door.
Der--I'll do it.
♪♪
Oh, what's this--aah!
Operator,
this is an emergency.
You must connect me
with the city electrical
generating plant.
Hurry!
He thinks he's
the wichita lineman! Quick!
[Phone ringing]
Generating plant.
Simpson here.
Hello?
Please listen to me.
You must do as I say.
The monster is coming towards
the town.
If you'd like to speak
to an operator, press one.
I'm at north ridge road.
We have a weapon here that might
be able to stop it
if we can connect it to the
power lines.
Who is this?
I'll have to check with--
wait, is this bob?
You have to believe me.
There's no time
to check with anybody!
♪♪
Whoa, time for my break.
Out there--
that looks like them.
Derek is
climbing down a pole.
And look what's coming.
We're not going to
make it down in time.
Oh!
♪♪
[Gargon wailing]
You have got to be
kidding me.
♪♪
Restore the power--
it is ready!
Hello?
Turn the power back on.
Okay!
Geez, can I get you
anything else?
How are you fixed for
socks and underwear?
♪♪
It is not enough.
It is not enough power!
Can you boost the power any?
Please, it's not enough!
I'll try to speed up
the generators.
I'm doing everything I can,
captain!
Derek seems to have
some kind of weapon,
but it's not doing anything!
[Gargon wailing]
[Imitating gargon's wail]
[Laughter]
[Electricity sizzling]
Oops.
Vapor action.
If only there were
more power, betty.
Is there any way
to generate more power?
We've got to have more!
I could join in more circuits,
but it may blow out the line.
Wait--he sounds
like derek.
Try anything!
It's our only chance!
Well, I could pull this
other power handle.
Oh, yeah.
That ought to do it.
Oh!
[Gargon wailing]
[Droning]
There we go.
♪♪
Rosebud.
Good night,
sweet crustacean.
♪♪
Gee, your hair
smells terrific.
♪♪
You can turn the weapon over to
the scientists now.
[High pitched tone]
Here's someone
who can help you.
[Derek]
It is too late.
You mean they're coming?
To take me away?
Already?
Your people are here for you.
I must leave.
My people
will call your people.
They will take care of you.
But, derek, you promised.
You said--
I know what I must do.
I have to take a meeting.
You must not interfere.
Bye.
♪♪
Betty, thank heavens
you're all right.
And thank goodness for
the new, generous cut
of my depends.
[Muffled shouting]
[Captain]
That book has indeed
made you forget many things.
We are the supreme race.
We have the supreme weapons.
Ah, turn rush limbaugh off.
Yeah.
♪♪
[Betty]
Somehow, I feel that
I've always known you,
that we've never been apart.
Boy, this guy can do
a lot of great voices.
Mm-hmm.
[Thor]
You are the son of our leader.
You remember
how to cook 'em.
Whenever there's a cop
beating up a guy,
I'll be there.
[Betty]
You won't be going back ever,
will you?
Tomorrow is another day.
Ask not what your country
can do for you.
How did he get
a weapon like that?
Makes me think of
what the killer used.
Grandpa, couldn't you
sit in back?
It is.
The same thing.
But who is he? Where did
he come from, anyway?
From someplace none of us has
ever heard of before, joe.
What do you mean?
[Speaking made-up chinese]
"Claire"
from another planet...
Oh, she came from
planet claire.
Far out in space.
Hey, wait a minute.
Betty, this is
no time to be joking.
I'm not joking.
I'm doing improv.
Where do you think
the monster came from?
And the man who was
doing all the killing
and the unheard-of
weapon he used.
A big crab, sure,
but a man from space?
They came in a spaceship
of some sort,
whatever those people told you
they saw last night.
The flying saucer?
And I thought those people were
seeing things.
Yeah, good reporter.
Really listens to people.
Derek looked into the sky
just before he left here.
Look to the sky.
Somehow, he could tell
that more are on the way.
What a fruitcake.
[High-pitched pinging]
[Singing to the tune
of leave it to beaver]
Whoa, it looks like it
took 'em all night to get home.
♪♪
Ah, cripes, I need a nap.
I haven't had one
in 45 minutes.
He must be in the house.
There's our car.
♪♪
[Gasps]
Derek!
You turned into
bobby goldsboro.
You know, everything
works but the shoes
and maybe those gloves.
♪♪
Good-bye, betty.
No, derek, no.
You are joe?
I am not.
I want you to take me
somewhere in your vehicle.
Disneyland.
What makes you think I will?
You refuse to take me?
That's right.
I'm staying right here.
You will do as I say.
No, derek,
this isn't you.
Do not interfere, betty,
I beg you. Get in.
No, we can't have a plot twist
this late in the movie.
[Groans]
Now, listen, if I
don't get in that car,
I'm gonna regret it,
maybe not today, maybe
not tomorrow, but soon.
Take me to where they are
keeping the prisoner.
The killer?
No, the prisoner.
He's at general hospital,
but--
then take me there.
I want to meet luke
and laura while I'm there.
Joe, don't--the disintegrator,
it won't--
betty!
No run-on sentences.
Trust me, betty.
Trust me.
♪♪
Oh, I like that.
They race to the scene
but they park carefully.
The prisoner is
in this building?
Looks like they haven't
transferred him
to city jail yet.
- What are you planning to do?
- Never mind.
I'm gonna try to catch oswald
in the parking ramp, but--
just get out of the car
and walk in front of me.
♪♪
Okay, now wet your lips
and work that booty.
♪♪
I have good posture,
I know I do.
♪♪
Hey, do you mind?
♪ Doo doo doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
Do not move.
I will take the prisoner.
Get their guns.
This is the most incompetent
prisoner transfer
since dallas '63.
Hand them to me.
Now get in.
Now dance! Dance!
Do the two-step!
[Whistling]
♪♪
Jack lalanne, everybody,
jack lalanne.
[Whistling and applauding]
Where's elaine?
- Elaine?
- Elaine lalanne.
Scooch over,
I'll ride raygun.
You face the wall.
Keep your hands above
your heads.
Okay, now, shake 'em!
I was stupid, thor.
Very stupid.
But that is over.
We are returning to
meet the ships, together.
Why do you let them live?
Kill them!
There is no need.
They will be
dead soon enough,
along with everything else
on this planet.
Go!
Like you've never
"goed" before.
♪♪
What's your dream, gramps?
[Air raid siren blares]
Uh, first wednesday
of the month.
Ships of an alien source are
approaching from the sky.
Radio contact has been attempted
but cannot be established.
Instructions are to prepare
for an attack by an unknown
enemy.
[Air raid siren continues]
Children lose the ability
to walk.
Oh, cripes, look at that.
I'll never get my bulbs in.
Hold me.
♪♪
Sure is pretty
up here, eh? Heh heh.
What made you think he was
coming here?
[All yawn]
Because they're coming.
To take me away, ha ha.
He told me they'd be coming.
He told me he wouldn't go back
with them, that he'd stay.
It looks like grandpa's got
an elaborate network of
trusses under that sweater.
That he wanted to stay.
Betty, let me
take you back home.
No, grandpa, look.
Here comes joe's car!
And as always, there's plenty of
free parking at the quarry.
Mm-hmm.
♪♪
The movie really picks up
from here, doesn't it?
Everybody gets to be
a hostage in this movie.
♪♪
Betty, gramps,
what are you doing here?
Why do you concern
yourself with them?
Destroy them!
Why, thor?
They cannot change
what is going to happen.
What is going
to happen, derek?
Subdivisions--
inevitable.
Walmarts, mega-mall--
lots of them.
You must understand.
I'm a magic man.
Death...must come to all.
Sooner to some.
Later to others.
Scarecrow, I'll miss you
least of all.
[High-pitched pinging]
The guide ship
is about to land.
We must go to meet it.
You promised, derek!
Don't you remember
your promise?
Here's your stupid ring back.
I have not forgotten it.
I had my feelers crossed.
But, uh-- I, uh--
what? Oh. Ooh.
[High-pitched pinging]
He called that
the guide ship.
Yeah, and they call
the wind mariah.
And it looks like there are
100 more still in the sky.
- What are they going to do?
- Derek told me.
I wish we could pan
over there, but, you know...
The other ships are loaded
with thousands of those
horrible creatures,
like the one
derek killed today.
Why are they
bringing them here?
For a mr. Steak
summertime bake and clambake.
To raise, for food
a safe distance from
their own people.
And they don't care
what happens to us?
Derek cared.
He wanted to make
the earth his home.
He promised
he would never leave.
Oh, your problems are the most
important, aren't they?
[Crying]
Oh, joe!
Oh, hey, joe.
I would have used the
disintegrator on them,
but it will not function
without energy supply.
You coulda.
Didn't wanna.
It was damaged
when you crashed.
I had to bluff with it.
It is just as well.
I sound like
gilbert gottfried.
They will be the first victims
of the gargon herds.
[Electronic humming]
Oh, your hair's done,
mrs. Anderson.
Oh, great,
it's mr. Torture again.
So you were able to
bring him back, thor.
[All]
Torture!
He...brought me.
I am sorry I...
Acted the way I did.
I am ready to take my
punishment.
There will be
no punishment, my son.
[Whistles]
Oh, well, there's got to
be at least two more russian
aviators in that thing.
You are my father?
I am.
I have watched your progress
since you were born.
You have excelled
in all things.
Give me that beard!
I was most disappointed to learn
that you had deserted.
I came this trip hoping
I would find you had returned.
Got any cough drops, dad?
Has what I have done not
disqualified me?
Am I still to--
you are back.
That is all that matters.
We'll kill
the fatted calf now.
Your mistakes were made
because of that book.
It blurred your mind,
but only temporarily.
What? Oh!
How is it you are able
to leave the planet?
It's a spaceship
and you just sort of--
will not the government
structure collapse
in your absence?
We will return immediately,
as soon as the gargons
are unloaded from
the fleet of ships.
The people are unaware
that I am gone.
Yes, we must leave quickly.
If your absence
were discovered,
it would likely spark the
beginning of a revolution.
I am not the only one
who had that book, father.
Yes, I know, and you will
help in tracking down others
who may have such books.
Yes, i-- I see the fleet is
approaching.
Made you look.
They are flying from radio
signals from the guide ship,
are they not?
Just a little torture!
Let me be the one to
direct them in for landing.
Captain, are the ships
close enough to receive
their landing signals?
Momentarily, but--
then go below, derek.
You will bring them in.
I'm convinced
he's turned bad.
Yeah, but--
but what about torture?
Safely, I'll just be
guiding them in. Ha!
No crashing. Ha!
Oh.
Suckers.
So long, screw ya,
see you in st. louya.
Derek, what are you doing?
Unbolt the hatch!
[Electronic beeping]
Mom, is that you
making that noise?
Looks like derek
went in first and closed
the entrance way.
Are we still in this movie?
Whatever's in the sky,
they're getting mighty close.
Derek has some plan.
He's not doing what
they want him to, I'm sure.
[Electronic beeping]
Oh, karaoke. I'd like to
sing rhinestone cowboy.
Master control to fleet,
master control to fleet.
Increase speed.
Set flight pattern
to minus .08.
[Leader]
Derek, I command you!
Do not do this!
- Increase speed.
- Open this hatch at once!
The ships seem to be converging
and increasing their speed.
They cannot land!
He does not plan to have
them land, but crash!
They're coming right at us!
Derek's doing it.
That's what he planned!
But he's inside there!
He'll be killed too!
Get down,
inside the cave!
Oh, lord,
let it be quick.
[Leader]
Derek, my son! Think,
think of what you are doing!
Turn the ships around
before it is too late!
Oh, bite me, dad,
you're so embarrassing!
Hold course steady.
[High-pitched pinging]
[Rumbling and whooshing]
They turned it
into mount vesuvius.
[Rumbling dies down]
Kingsford tonight.
[Fire crackling]
Ah, the foley man's
frying up a burger.
Oh, criminy, there's little
chunks of derek everywhere.
Yecch.
Eh, toss sparky into a bag.
Let's get out of here.
It's beautiful up here,
isn't it?
♪♪
Joe, do you want to
get back together?
♪♪
♪ somewhere ♪
- It's his graduation photo.
- Wow.
I shall make the earth
my home, and I shall
never, never leave it.
You know, he first
had one taken with
his hockey uniform,
but he opted for that one.
Sing us out of here,
derek!
♪ Doo doo doo doo doo ♪
Many of the mercury players
have never been in films before.
Here are some of them.
Oh, let's go home.
I've got a room to rent out.
Look to this day,
young graduate,
as you move on
into your new life.
♪♪
Mechanical whirring]
In today's experiment,
our alien teenager's
slenderizing attractive
space garb
is obviously a clever
combination of $30 off-the-rack
fleet farm coveralls
and just the right amount
of duct tape.
Well, our fall line is out,
and weren't we just the
teensiest bit inspired
by today's experiment?
- Mm-hmm.
- You bet.
[Laughs]
So, cambot,
our first model, please?
[Clears throat]
Inspired by
the practical frivolity
of a donna karan,
here's joel, cavorting
in a peppy jumper
accented with
red duct tape piping
for the right amount of
come hither sensuality.
I've taken a daring approach
for our fetching lad,
eh, mr. Crow?
Oui, oui, monsieur.
But wait, isn't that gadabout
gadfly tom servo
in my calf-length tunic
with opaque leggings
striped with a teasing
smack of bright but serious
perma-seal gaffer tape?
[Laughs]
Well, now,
I wanted to see crow
in something a little co-ed
that absolutely screams fall,
and by golly,
didn't I get it?
Coverall meets polo in this
rugged tape-striped
rugger jersey,
with a khaki pant and
a touch of merry old england.
Eh, what?
What? What?
Oh! Oh! My turn.
[Clears throat]
And just in time
for the cruise season,
and our little cruiser
sports my sassy nautical theme
in a navy coverall
with white gaffer piping.
It's gusseted for an easy feel,
and guess what?
Bellbottoms are back,
and just in time.
Well, you can swab my deck
anytime, sailor.
By the by, you were a dream
at the shoot session.
I'll work with you
any old time.
Well, from ship to shore,
tommy.
Now, how many times
has this happened to you?
Dinner, mr. President?
Tonight?
Why, sure!
Now, what do you do?
My versatile black cotton
broadcloth
with shiny gloss
duct-tape lapels and accents
comes to the rescue
with our little ingenue.
From chaos to kennebunkport
in minutes.
And just in time.
Evening may be tom's,
but the night belongs to crow.
Wow, my eyes
can't help but turn
at the sight of this
magnificent little nothing.
Yes, it's the classic
joe namath netted
slingshot hoop.
Joel, joel, joel,
joel-- cambot! Yeah,
that's enough, that's enough!
Uh, joel, come on.
What? What?
I thought we agreed
not to show that one.
Uh, things got a little carried
away at the photo session.
We were discussing jfk
the film, and one thing led
to another and--ha ha! Well!
Honey, if you've got it,
flaunt it, you know?
Well, let's do a letter,
okay?
Yeah, let's read a letter,
shall we?
I thought you
looked very, very--
well, this one says,
"dear joe..."
Uh, let's put this up
on still story, cambot.
It says, "my 'who'
family likes your shows,
'exept' my mom.
"She hates the jokes
you make.
"We all are fans
'exept' for her.
"What should we do.
The ahmadi's,
san jose, ca."
And it shows
an unhappy mom.
Just tell mom to wait for
lawrence welk to come back.
Ooh, what a burn.
That's somebody's mother.
Scorch.
This next one comes from--
I'll put it up
on the still story--
the gamera team,
university of kentucky
college of medicine.
"Dear joel, 'crowe,'
tom servo, and gypsy:
"A number of us here on earth
at the university of kentucky
college of medi--"
stop it. "Were greatly
inspired by the gamera movies
shown last year on mst.
"So inspired, in fact, that we
named our pediatrics ward team
after gamera himself
and became
'the gamera team.'"
and let's show
a picture of them.
And that's some
of the young--
not very good.
- They'll be doctors someday.
- No, it's fine.
I feel secure and safe,
knowing that they're gonna be
practicing medicine
on human beings.
What do you think, sirs?
[Laughs]
And then the--
and then the clam says,
"I thought
I was a bivalve."
[Laughs]
Oh, I see
you've heard that one.
Oh.
Excuse me, dear.
Joel, I was
just entertaining.
Until next time, uh...
Pour the wine and then
push the button, louie.
Oui, oui, monsieur.
[Laughs]
Help me.
So, have I told you
I have a man up in space?
No, literally, I have
a man up in space.
♪♪
When we return
to our planet,
the high court may well
sentence you to torture!